卡塞尔  这件怎么样
Castle, what do you think of this one?
好性感
Mm. Sexy.
性感  你说性感是什么意思
Sexy? What do you mean by sexy?
我意思是
I mean...
没错  就是性感
Well, I-I mean sexy.
性感  性感哪里不好了
Yeah, sexy. What's wrong with sexy?
老天  卡塞尔  这可是我复职第一天
Oh, god, Castle. This is my first day back at work.
应该穿得正常低调
I'm supposed to look normal.
没人能通过你的穿着看出
No one is going to be able to tell that we're together
我们在一起了
by how you are dressed.
是吗  别忘了我的同事可全是警探
Oh, no? I only work with a roomful of detectives.
他们都是靠这吃饭的
It's their job.
这件怎么样
What about this one?
不行
No.
你只是想让我再次脱掉衣服  对吧
You just want me to take my shirt off again, don't you?
-什么  -别闹了
- What? - Stop it.
我跟你说过了  纽约警局对于
I told you, the NYPD has a strict policy
同事恋情有着严格的规定
about coworkers... dating.
对  但我只是打义务工的
Yes, but since I'm not getting paid,
-所以严格说来我们不是同事  -是吗
- technically, we're not coworkers. - Oh, really?
你觉得盖茨也会这样想吗
And you think that captain Gates is gonna see it that way?
如果有人发现了  并让她听到了风声
If anyone finds out, and she gets wind of it--
没人会发现的
No one is going to find out.
我连我妈和阿丽克西斯都没告诉
I haven't even told my mother or Alexis.
那是因为她们在欧洲
Yeah, that's because they're in Europe
庆祝你闺女高中毕业
celebrating her graduation.
没错  但我也没打长途电话告诉她们
Yes, true. But I haven't told them long distance.
听我说  没人会发现的
Look, no one is going to find out.
不过安全起见
But just to be safe,
你还是换条裤子吧
you might want to change out of those pants.
曼哈顿上城发生了命案
Oh, there's a murder uptown.
看来你是没时间换裤子了
And looks like the pants stay on.
卡塞尔  记住  要装作没事
Castle, remember, act normal.
我们在公众地方时  你是单身  我也是单身
And when we're in public, you're single and I'm single.
-明白吗  -明白
- Got it? - Got it.
多谢
Thanks.
这么说不能拼车去咯
So that's a no to carpooling then?
我坐出租车好了
I'll take a cab.
早上好  贝克特探长
Good morning, detective Beckett.
卡塞尔  我的咖啡呢
Castle, where is my coffee?
你已经喝过了
You already had one.
过去四年来你一直帮我买咖啡
You've been bringing me coffee for the past four years.
我说了要装作没事  这样看起来会很可疑
I told you to act normal. This is gonna look suspicious.
放心吧  没事的
Don't worry. Relax.
你想多了  真的
You're overthinking this, really.
什么情况  居然没咖啡
What, no coffee?
我忘了帮她买
I forgot hers.
你忘了
You forgot?
她停职后复职的第一天
On her first day back from suspension?
没事  我已经原谅他了
It's all right. I've already forgiven him.
被害人身份知道了吗
So who's our vic?
本地名人
Local celeb.
管理员今天早上发现她被塞在
Groundskeeper found her tucked behind this fountain
喷泉后面
early this morning.
她是WHNY台的天气预报员  曼迪·麦克斯
She's actually the weather girl for WHNY--Mandy Michaels.
-曼迪·麦克斯  -对
- Mandy michaels? - Yeah.
-真的假的  -真的
- Really? - Yeah.
不是吧  我每晚都看她的节目
Oh, man. I watched her every night.
她有着最棒的...
She had the best...
天气预报
forecasts.
怎么了  听着  作为单身男士
What? Listen, as a single man,
我很欣赏她的"可取之处"
I appreciated her assets.
你可别说大家看她的节目是为了听天气预报
You can't tell me people watched her for the weather.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
谢谢
Thank you.
你...  是不是有什么变化啊
You--what, are you doing something different?
没啊  怎么了
No. Why?
说不上来  气场有点不一样
I don't know. Something's changed.
死因是什么
So how'd she die?
死于枪击
Single G.S.W.
昨晚10:28接到报警附近居民称听到枪声
Shot was called in by neighbors last night at 10:28 P.M.
时间与尸斑情况吻合
Which fits lividity.
有搏斗过的迹象
There's also signs of a struggle.
被害人上臂有伤痕
Vic has bruises on her upper arm
衣服也破了
and her blouse was ripped.
没找到钱包  皮包及手机
There's no sign of a wallet, purse, or phone.
听起来像是抢劫失控
Sounds like a mugging gone wrong.
说话这阵儿技术人员正在定位她的手机
I got tech pinging her phone as we speak.
说到这个  我去看看结果
Speaking of which, I'm gonna go check on that.
你们还在闹别扭吗
You guys still haven't buried the hatchet?
该怎样就怎样
It is what it is.
据WHNY台曼迪的制作人说
So according to Mandy's producer at WHNY,
摄制组最后看到她
she was last seen
是在市立儿童医院
by her camera crew doing a weather spot
做天气节目
at city of trust children's hospital
时间是昨晚九点半
last night at 9:30 P.M.
离这里有20条街
That's 20 blocks from here.
是  而且曼迪的公寓在另一个方向
Yeah, and Mandy's apartment's the other direction.
所以她收工一小时后会在公园里做什么呢
So what was she doing here in the park an hour later?
喂
Yo.
曼迪的手机是开着的
Mandy's phone is active.
技术人员追踪到了GPS信号
Tech tracked her GPS signal
位置是下东区的一栋建筑
to a building on the lower east side.
看来找到抢劫犯了
Sounds like our mugger.
好的  你们去那边看看
All right, you guys check in to it.
卡塞尔和我会找死者家属谈谈
Castle and I will talk to next of kin.
-我还是...  -我想...
- Yeah, I'd pr-- - You know, I'd be much--
快去吧  行吗
Just--just go. Okay?
信号来自这层楼的一个房间
The signal's coming from one of the rooms on this floor.
问题是  哪个房间
The question is, which one?
你干嘛呢
What the hell are you doing?
做个优秀的警察  缩小范围
Being a good cop, narrowing down my options.
你呢
What are you doing?
就这儿
Right here. Right here.
纽约警局
NYPD!
举起双手  不许动
Hands, now! Don't move!
我什么也没做
I didn't do anything.
我发誓
I swear.
那是她的手机
That's her phone.
不
No.
这是我的手机
It's my phone.
我猜那也是你的皮包咯
I suppose that's your purse, too?
乔纳森·古德哈特
Jonathan Goodheart.
你可是做了不少坏事啊  乔纳森
You have been a very, very bad boy, Jonathan.
叫我乔尼
It's Johnny.
档案上写着  乔纳森  你有
It says here, Jonathan, that you
跟踪的前科
have priors for stalking,
猥亵露阴
Indecent exposure.
跟踪的事儿是个误会  还有
That stalking was a misunderanding, and...
另一件事儿发生那天实在太热了
That other thing happened on a really hot day.
反正你什么事都有借口
Well, you just have an explanation for everything,
是吧  乔纳森
don't you, Jonathan?
那你就给我解释下
So why don't you explain to me
你怎么会有曼迪·麦克斯的皮包
what you were doing with Mandy Michaels' purse.
我捡到的
I found it.
你捡到的
You found it?
在莱克星敦街和第九大道交界的垃圾箱里
In a dumpster on Lexington and 9th.
包很软
It was soft.
我喜欢软软的东西
I like things that are soft.
多保重  麦克斯太太
Yeah, take care, Ms. Michaels.
你还好吗
You okay?
我刚和曼迪的父母通完电话
Well, I-I just got off the phone with Mandy's parents.
他们说她大部分时间都在工作
They said that she spent most of her time at work.
没有男朋友
There was no boyfriend,
他们不知道为什么她会去公园
and they have no idea why she was in the park.
两位  看这个
Hey, guys. Check this out.
我检查了曼迪的皮包
I was going through Mandy's purse,
发现这个折叠放在她的包里
And I found this folded up in her wallet.
"如果走漏半点风声  我就杀了你"
"If any of this gets out, I'll kill you"?
我可以大胆判断她被人威胁了
I'm gonna go ahead and say she was being threatened.
但并不代表这就是她的被害原因
That doesn't mean this is why she was killed.
所有证据都表明  她是被劫杀的
All the evidence points to the fact that she was mugged.
那不是劫杀
It wasn't a mugging.
你怎么知道的
How can you tell?
她衬衫上的血迹表明
Blood spatter on her blouse indicates
衬衫是在枪击之后才撕开的
the shirt was ripped after the gunshot.
那她身上的淤青呢
What about the bruising?
死后才造成的
Postmortem.
为了伪装得像劫杀
To make it look like a mugging.
有人试图掩盖踪迹
Someone's trying to cover their tracks.
说到这个
Speaking of which,
我终于想明白你有什么不同了
I figured out what's different.
你做爱了
You're having sex.
你说什么
Excuse me?
别想抵赖
Oh, don't try to deny it.
你脸上红光焕发  我很清楚那种红光
There's a glow. I know that glow.
快说那个男人是谁
So who's the guy?
是啊  贝克特  那男人是谁啊
Yeah, Beckett, who's the guy?
反正不是你认识的人  行了吧
Nobody that you would know, okay?
你确定吗  我可是认识很多人的
Are you sure? I know a lot of guys.
我很确定  还有别的信息吗
I'm sure. Anything else?
实际上
As a matter of fact,
我在曼迪的衬衫上发现的化妆品
I found makeup on Mandy's blouse
比她身上用的清淡得多
that's much lighter than the shade that she wears.
沾在此处表明二人曾近距离接触
The position indicates close contact,
就像她曾和某人打过架
like she fought with someone.
彻查全城使用清淡化妆品的女性
Rounding up all the women in the city who wear lighter makeup
可是个大工程啊
is a pretty wide net.
那可不是普通的化妆品
It isn't just any makeup.
是为高清摄像头专门设计的
It's formulated for high-definition cameras.
比如电视台常用的那种
Like the ones they use at TV stations.
与此同时  执法部门正全力追查
In the meantime, authorities are still on the hunt
曼迪·麦克斯被害案的嫌疑人
for suspects in the Mandy Michaels slaying.
尽管警方并未透露过多细节
Though few details have been released,
但我们可以确定  她是昨夜被枪杀的
we can confirm that she was shot to death late last night
地点是佩里公园
in Paley park.
我想代表电视台的全体工作人员说一句
Speaking on behalf of the entire broadcast community,
以后的五日天气预报将与以往不同了
The 5-day forecast just won't be the same.
查克
Chuck?
谢谢你  迈尔斯
Thank you, Miles.
我们会随着破案进度继续报道这一悲痛事件
We'll bring you more on this difficult story as events unfold.
接下来要报道的是
But coming up next,
你每天清晨喝的咖啡可能会要了你的命
Your morning coffee could be killing you.
稍后为您带来详细报道
We'll have that story when we come back.
接下来是广告时间
and we're out to commercial.
大家都很悲痛
Everyone here is devastated.
我们就像一家人
We're like a family.
什么样的家庭  幸福的还是不和的
What kind of family, happy or dysfunctional?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
意思就是  作为电视台台长
Meaning, as the station manager,
你应该很清楚自己手下的人事情况
you would know your personnel.
她和谁有过节吗
Did she have any conflicts with anyone?
当然  但我不觉得
Sure, but I-I can't imagine
那和她的被害有关
that has anything to do with what happened.
谁和她有过节
Well, who was it?
另一个女性天气预报员  瑞贝卡·弗格
The other weather girl, Rebecca Fog.
弗格[雾]真是她的姓吗
Is Fog her real name?
她们是为什么起冲突的
And what was the conflict?
瑞贝卡是新来的气象学家
Rebecca was the new meteorologist.
她野心勃勃  对曼迪步步紧逼
She was ambitious and nipping at Mandy's heels.
最近有发生什么事吗
Had anything happened recently?
实际上  她们确实才闹过一场架
As a matter of fact, they did just get into a bit of a scuffle.
是吗  什么时候的事
Really, when was this?
就昨晚  我带你们看
Last night. I'll show you.
抱歉  奇普  我们要借用播放台
Sorry, Chip. We need the bay.
好的  哈维
Yeah, sure, Harvey.
怎么了
What's up?
鲍勃  我需要那盘未播出的录像
Bob, I need the unaired footage
就是曼迪昨晚在信城医院拍的那段
from Mandy's segment last night at city of trust.
警察需要查看关于曼迪的录像
The police need to see some tape on Mandy.
是啊  那事太可怕了
Yeah, that was a terrible thing.
哇  说到纽约警察
Whoa. Talk about New York's finest.
她真是个警察吗
She really a cop?
是的  她真是警察
Yes, she's really a cop.
我叫奇普·钱伯斯  报道体育新闻的
Chip Chambers. I do sports.
欢迎你随时逮捕我
And you can arrest me anytime.
好啊  或许我真会的
Yeah, well, maybe I will.
就是这段
That's it.
以上就是近期天气预报  观众们
Well, that's your weather, folks,
出自我口  传至您家
straight from my lips to your living room.
这是曼迪·麦克斯从信城儿童医院
This is Mandy Michaels reporting live from the Toy Drive
为您带来的现场报道
at the city of Trust Children's Hospital.
好了
And we're clear.
瑞贝卡
Rebecca?
你他妈跑过来干什么
What the hell are you doing here?
你心里清楚我过来干什么
You know exactly what I'm doing here,
-你个耍阴谋的贱人  -放开我
- You conniving bitch! - Hey, knock it off.
你不知道你惹的是谁
You have no idea who you're dealing with.
怎么回事
What happened?
摄像师关掉了摄像机去劝架了
The cameraman turned off his camera and broke up the fight.
他看见瑞贝卡离开了吗
Did he see Rebecca leave?
没有  她们冷静下来之后
No. Once they settled down,
他就走了  剩她们二人继续谈
he left them there talking.
那肯定是一场奇"谈"啊
Well, it must have been a hell of a talk.
一小时后  曼迪就死了
An hour later, Mandy was dead.
听着  曼迪·麦克斯是个懒惰
Look, mandy michaels was a lazy,
资深  胸大的蠢女人
entitled, big-boobed bimbo.
我一来就开始做那些她挑剩的活儿
I've been picking up her slack since the minute I got here.
"哈维  我不能坐直升机报道交通实况"
"Harvey, "I can't go in the helicopter for 'traffic live!'
"因为我有哮喘
"Because of my asthma.
让瑞贝卡去干吧"
Make Rebecca do it."
我讨厌她吗  当然
I mean, did I hate her? Yes.
但我不会杀她的
But I would never kill her.
不过现在她死了
Except now that she's dead,
你可以从凌晨4点的时间档
you get to trade in 4:00 A.M. shift
调到极具诱惑的晚间新闻档  是吧
for the coveted and lucrative evening news spot, right?
拜托
Oh, please.
我不需要为那个杀了她
I didn't need to kill her for that.
我只要再等等就行了
I just needed to wait.
她的巅峰时期已经过了
She was already past her sell-by date.
根据哈维的说法
Well, according to Harvey,
她依然有很多忠实的观众
she still had a very loyal audience.
是啊  但那些人
Sure. Yeah, people who cared
只关心她的衬衫开了几颗纽扣
about how many buttons on her blouse were open.
但她那个年纪  在高清电视环境下
But at her age in high def,
她很快就会被观众抛弃的
she was running out of buttons fast.
你俩打架又是怎么回事  弗格小姐
Then what was the fight about, Ms. Fog?
我是个有证书的气象学家  好吗
Look, I'm a certified meteorologist. Okay?
我是靠大脑的
I have a brain.
曼迪不过是靠风骚姿色混到了现在
Mandy was just set dressing with cleavage.
我的预报比她的要准确的多
My forecasts were way more accurate than hers,
而且人们也开始注意到了
And people were starting to notice.
所以上周  她为了报复我  闯入我的办公室
So last week, to get back at me, she breaks into my office,
偷走了我的一堆设备
she steals a bunch of my equipment.
所以我才去找她对质
I mean, that's why I went to confront her.
但就那样  仅此而已
But that's it. That's all.
昨晚10:28你在哪里
Where were you at 10:28 last night?
在家睡觉
Home sleeping.
我凌晨四点要上班的  记得吗
I mean, I have the 4:00 A.M. shift, remember?
而且  她比我早离开那家儿童医院
And besides, she left the children's hospital before I did.
你们想查出是谁杀害了曼迪
You want to find out who killed Mandy,
就去问开着银色奔驰车接她的人吧
ask the person in the silver g-wagon who picked her up.
什么人
What person?
我不知道  你问倒我了
I don't know. Beats me.
那车的车窗贴着防透视玻璃
The car had tinted windows,
但她肯定认识他们
But it sure seemed like she knew them.
瑞贝卡的不在场证明是真的
So Rebecca was telling the truth about where she was.
她用信用卡付的出租车钱
She paid for the cab with a credit card,
在曼迪被害之前
and the cabbie dropped her off at her apartment
司机就把她送回了家
before Mandy was killed.
好吧  那查查交通摄像头
Okay. Yeah, so check traffic cams
和监控录像  看有没有银色的奔驰
and surveillance in the area for the silver G-Wagon.
运气好的话  我们...
Yeah, I mean, if we're lucky, we'll...
也许能查到车牌
we might actually get a plate.
你能追查通话记录
So, uh, were you able to track down the phone records
看看她那晚是否打过电话吗
to see if she made any calls that night?
好的
Okay.
理查德  理查德·卡塞尔
Richard. Richard castle.
克里斯蒂娜  好久不见...
Kristina. Oh, I have not seen you...
自从...
Since...
自从我在红毯上采访了你
Since I interviewed you on the red carpet
你还答应要来我的节目呢
and you promised to do my show.
没错  我是答应了
Oh, that's right. I did.
弗雷德·威拉德今晚放我鸽子了
Fred Willard canceled on me tonight.
我没有嘉宾了  真是命中注定啊
I don't have a guest. I feel like it's fate.
我得挂电话了  埃斯波  再见
Okay. I gotta go, Espo. Bye.
-今晚  -九点
- Tonight? - 9:00.
我可不接受拒绝哦
I'm not taking no for an answer.
那我就不推拒了
Well, then I won't say no.
很好  回头见  里奇
Good. I'll see you soon, Ricky.
好的
All right.
那只是他们电视台的娱记
Oh, that's just their entertainment reporter.
她...我经纪人一直催着我
She's... My agent has been haranguing me
去宣传《冰冻希特》...
to promote "Frozen Heat", so...
她不就是那个
Isn't she the reporter
穿着比基尼上节目的记者吗
that shows up to cover stories in her bikini?
是吧  我  我没留意
Yeah, y--I don't--is-- I didn't notice that.
要不要再说一次
You want to try it again,
看看能不能装得更像一点
make it sound a little more convincing?
不用了
No, I'm good.
他们俩正在搜寻那辆神秘车
Okay. So the boys are running down our mystery car.
同时  他们在曼迪的通话记录中也有发现
In the meantime, they found something on Mandy's phone records.
她一直接到一个匿名手机号的电话
She was getting calls from an anonymous burner cell.
事实上  她死前接到的最后一通电话
In fact, the last call she got before her murder
-就来自这个号码  -但我们无法追踪
- was from that number. - But there's no way to trace it.
也许有办法  这些通话记录有个模式
Yeah, there might be. There's a pattern on the calls,
大多数都在工作日凌晨两点到四点拨入
and most of them came in on weekdays between 2:00 and 4:00.
就在她的天气预报之前
That's right before her broadcast.
也就是说她在这里
Which means she was here.
没错  曼迪两点到四点是在这里
Yeah, Mandy was here between 2:00 and 4:00.
她上镜前需要多画点妆
She needed all the time in that chair she could get.
女人一旦到了三十五岁
When a woman hits mid-30s,
那些高清摄像机很快就能出卖你的年龄
those H.D. cameras can turn on you fast.
比我前夫在床上的速度还快
Faster-than-my-ex-husband in-the-sack fast.
我们想问问她到这里以后
You know, we were wondering about a series of phone calls
接到的那些电话
that she might have gotten while she was here.
她的秘密男友
Her secret man.
秘密男友
Secret man?
曼迪从不隐瞒自己的感情生活
Mandy was always open about her love life,
但只要这家伙打电话来
but when this guy would call,
她就会离开房间
she'd leave the room.
她想低调行事
She was keeping it on the down low.
你总觉得自己很小心谨慎了
Yeah, you always think you're being so discreet,
不过相信我  群众的眼睛是雪亮的
but trust me, people know.
那你们知道那个神秘男友是谁吗
So do you guys have any idea who he is?
知道  几周前我去外面的
Yeah. A few weeks ago I went outside
自动贩卖机买个坚果黄油饼干
to get a nutter butter from the vending machine,
无意中听到他们在谈论他的重大比赛
and I overheard them talking about his big game.
他是个运动员
He's an athlete?
还是最有价值球员呢
More like an M.V.P.
本地一支非常出名的篮球队中的一员
Of a very well-known local basketball team.
17号有没有让你想起谁
Does the number 17 ring a bell?
雷吉·布雷克
Reggie Blake?
她在和雷吉·布雷克交往
She was dating Reggie Blake?
卡塞尔  他不是已婚了吗
Castle, isn't he married?
不止已婚了
Yeah, not only is he married,
传闻说  他的婚前协议
but rumor has it, he has a very strict
严令禁止出轨
no-cheating clause in their prenup.
根据他的收入  离婚可是要花大价钱的
Based on his income, it'd be very costly if he got a divorce.
再猜猜他开什么车的
And guess what he drives.
-银色奔驰  -没错
- A silver G-Wagon? - Yep.
好了  带他来一趟吧
All right, pick him up.
让一下  让让  让他过去
Make a hole. Make a hole. Give him room.
见到你真好  阿雷
Good to see you, Reg!
谢谢
Ah, thanks. Appreciate it.
很高兴见到你  兄弟
Oh, good to see you, man.
我打头阵吧
Let me take the lead.
随便了
Whatever.
怎么了  我经验丰富
What? I got more experience.
哈维  在对付这家伙的时候
Yo, Javi, do you mind if we call a time-out
咱俩先停战行吗
while we collar this guy, huh?
-再见  -雷吉
- A'ight. - Reggie.
雷吉  雷吉
Reggie. Reggie.
伙计们  今天不签名了
Fellas. No autographs today.
我们是纽约警察
We're NYPD.
就算是中情局也不行
I don't give a hobo's crap if you're CIA.
不签名了
No autographs.
我们不是来要签名的  我们来请雷吉走一趟
We're not here for autographs. We're here for Reggie.
而你在妨碍公务
And you're obstructing our investigation.
让开
So move.
就该这样
That's what I thought.
见鬼
Oh, hell.
雷吉哪里都不去
You're not taking Reggie anywhere.
让路
Get out of the way, man.
他们怎么还没回来
Shouldn't they be back by now?
可能路上堵车了
Well, maybe they hit traffic.
或者赌气吧
Or each other.
不管怎样  雷吉这下惨了
Either way, Reggie is going down.
警员彻查了曼迪的住所
UNIS canvassed Mandy's building,
邻居说在她被害当天
and neighbors said that they heard her
听到了她和一个男人吵架
in a yelling match with a guy the day that she was killed.
他们说听起来像是情侣间的口角
They said it sounded like a lover's quarrel.
感情破裂  婚姻危机
Relationship goes bad, his marriage is threatened...
所以雷吉威胁她说
so Reggie threatens her with the note.
"要是走漏半点风声  我就杀了你"
"If this gets out, I'll kill you."
她不肯乖乖听话  雷吉就干了他最擅长的事
She refuses to play ball, so Reggie does what he does best--
开枪杀人[也有投篮之意]
starts shooting.
别问
Don't ask.
两位  我很抱歉
Look, man, I'm sorry.
我的安保人员护主心切
My security guys are protective.
那附近有不少疯子
We get a lot of nut bars hanging around the block.
不接受道歉
Apology not accepted.
坐下
Now sit down.
我说过了
Look, I told you,
我和她的凶杀案无关
I didn't have anything to do with her murder.
但我们有目击者看到曼迪
And yet, we have witnesses that saw Mandy
在被害前不久还上了你的车
get in to your car shortly before she was killed.
我们知道你俩在偷情  雷吉
We know about the affair, Reggie.
你妻子知道的话一定会勃然大怒吧
Can't imagine your wife would be too happy if she found out,
于是你确保了她不会知晓此事
so you made sure she didn't.
你们说什么呢  什么偷情
What are you talking about, affair?
我是认识曼迪  我妻子也认识她
Yeah, I knew Mandy. So did my wife.
我们是朋友  仅此而已
We were friends. That's all.
你觉得我们信吗  雷吉
You really expect us to believe that, Reggie?
这是事实  不信的话  尽管问我妻子
It's the truth. If you don't believe me, ask my wife.
我们会去问的
Oh, we will.
那你在曼迪播报结束之后
So I imagine it was just a coincidence
刚好驾车经过医院
that you happened to be driving by the hospital
这一切不过是巧合而已了
right after Mandy's segment ended.
不  我们都是医院慈善会的董事
No. We're both on the hospital charity board.
我过去捐些玩具
I was stopping by the toy drive.
我说了  我们只是朋友
I'm telling you, we were just friends.
如果"只是朋友"
Well, there sure are a lot of phone calls to Mandy,
那你给曼迪打的电话也太多了吧
considering you all are just friends.
曼迪和我
Mandy and I...
我们的职业生涯都进入倒计时了
We both had a ticking clock on our careers--
她的脸蛋  我的膝盖
Her looks, my knees.
能跟理解自己的人聊天  感觉很好
It was nice to chat with somebody who understood.
那好  就算你们"只是朋友"
Okay, say you were just friends.
为什么她不想让她的同事
Why didn't she want her coworkers
知道你和他的关系呢
to find out about you?
因为会招来绯闻啊
Because that's how rumors get started.
我知道你们会怎么想
I know what you're thinking.
我是名职业运动员
I'm a professional athlete,
她是个美女气象预报员
She's a blonde weather girl,
但事情不是你们想的那样
But it wasn't like that.
她不是那样的人
She wasn't like that.
那些在福利院的孩子们
Those kids at city of trust,
对于其他名人来说  只是个作秀的幌子
to other celebs, they was just a photo op.
但对她来说不是  她真的关心那些孩子
Not to her. She cared.
你们该看看她上个星期为孩子们做了什么
You should seen her last week,
向他们提问题
asking them questions,
倾听他们的故事
listening to their stories.
别人都以为她生活不检点
People think she's some kind of bimbo,
其实她并非那样
But she wasn't.
总之  我之前看见她拦下一辆出租车
Anyway, I-I saw her hailing a cab.
我就提出载她一程
I offered her a ride.
她让我送她到公园
She asked to be dropped off at the park.
那时大约是十点
That happened around 10:00.
10:28的时候你在哪
Where were you at 10:28?
我去了城市另一边的X酒吧
I was across town at X bar,
为我的新款鞋子做促销
Promoting my new shoe line.
不信你们去查
Check it.
曼迪有没有说她为什么
Mandy mention why she wanted
要去公园
to get dropped off at the park?
没说  她看上去有些紧张
No. She seemed nervous.
或许跟几天前
Maybe it had something to do
发生的那件事有关
with what happened a couple of days ago.
几天前发生了什么事
What happened a couple of days ago?
她在急诊室给我打电话让我去接她
She called me for a ride from the emergency room.
我问她发生什么事了  但她不肯说
I asked her what happened, but she wouldn't say.
等等  她是去就诊的吗
Wait. She was there as a patient?
是的
Yeah.
她看起来不像有恙  但看得出她很沮丧
She didn't look hurt, but she seemed pretty upset.
你相信他们"只是朋友"吗
Do you actually buy this whole "Just friends" thing?
这很合情
It's possible.
对  是合情  但不合理
Yeah, it's possible, but it's not probable.
说不清  咱俩这四年不就在只是朋友吗
I don't know. You and I were just friends for four years.
是啊  只是你这四年一直都想跟我上床
Yeah, except you were trying to sleep with me that whole time.
开什么玩笑
What?
纠正一下
Excuse me.
是你一直想跟我上床
It was you that was trying to sleep with me.
别告诉我你穿成那样是给埃斯波西托看的
Don't tell me you dress like that for Esposito.
给我看什么
What's for me?
-没什么  -啥也没有
- Nothing. - Don't worry about it.
雷吉的不在场证据被证实了
Reggie's alibi is solid.
曼迪遇害时他已经在X酒吧
He was already at the X bar buying shots for everyone
请大家喝酒了
when Mandy was killed.
他的妻子也证实了他们只是朋友关系
His wife confirms that they were all just friends.
实际上  是他妻子
In fact, she's the one
给他买了那部预付款手机
who bought him that prepaid cell phone
因为他的手机好像被黑了
Because his was hacked or something.
好吧  那就去联系几天前
Okay, then touch base with the E.R. doctor
给曼迪看病的那个急诊室医生
that treated Mandy a couple of days ago.
造成她去医院的原因
Whatever landed her in emergency
可能会告诉我们昨天晚上发生了什么
might have caught up with her last night.
-伙计们  我发现了  -等等
- Hey, guys. I found out who Mandy. -Yo.
你化妆了吗
Are you wearing makeup?
没有
No.
真的
Really?
一个小时前  咱俩都被打成了熊猫眼
Because an hour ago, you and I both had black eyes,
可你这么快就没事了
and now you don't.
不是的  这不是化妆
No, this is not makeup.
只是用了些有色面霜
This is tinted moisturizer.
刚才珍妮来了
Jenny just stopped by,
她包里恰好有些这种面霜
She happened to have some in her purse,
我想既然  你懂的
and I figured since the, you know--
算了  你爱怎么想就怎么想吧
Fine. Just judge all you want.
我查到曼迪遇害那天是谁在她家
So I found out who Mandy was fighting with at her apartment
跟她吵架了
the day she died.
她家街对面的那家商店
The store across the street from her building
装了监控摄像
uses surveillance.
录像显示雷吉并没有出现在那
There was no sign of Reggie,
但是我发现了另一个熟悉的面孔
But I did see another familiar face--
WHNY的播报员迈尔斯·哈克斯顿
WHNY reporter Miles Haxton.
没错  那是我
Yeah, that's me.
那么你去她家做什么呢
So what were you doing at her place?
曼迪的邻居们听到你们在吵架
Mandy's neighbors overheard the two of you fighting.
你们为什么要吵架
What was it about?
因为我们的关系
Our relationship.
你们在恋爱
You were dating?
你之前怎么不告诉我们
Why didn't you tell us this before?
因为我担心这件事会传出去
'Cause I couldn't take the chance that it would get out.
播报员和预报员搞到一起  绝不能传出去
The--the reporter and the weather girl? No.
电视台对办公室恋情有
This--this station has a very strict policy
很严格的纪律
about interoffice dating.
即使曼迪现在已经死了
And even--even with what happened to Mandy,
哈维仍然可能会把我停职的
Harvey still would've suspended me.
你们恋爱多少时间了
How long had the two of you been seeing each other?
有几个月了
Couple months.
你们的感情出了什么问题
What went wrong?
这是同事间搞地下情的通病
Well, here's the thing about a secret workplace romance, okay?
刚开始大家都很有激情
In the beginning, you're on a high.
每次偷情时的感觉就像给你的心脏
Every stolen moment feels like a-a shot of adrenaline
打了一针兴奋剂
straight to the heart.
甚至在上班路上都无比兴奋
You--you get butterflies on your way into work.
你感到既惊险又刺激
It's exciting and dangerous,
做爱时也很爽
and the sex is amazing.
然后呢
And then what?
然后我们自己会慢慢受不了
And then it imploded.
我们无法隐藏这么多的秘密
We were never gonna keep up the secret.
我们已经淹没在自己的各种谎言中了
We were already drowning in all the lies we had to tell.
你们的同事发现了你们的关系吗
Did--did your coworkers ever find out?
还没有
Uh, not yet.
但我要在这段感情毁掉
But I-I had to stay out in front of it
我们两个的事业之前结束它
to keep it from destroying both of our careers.
我是说我还有进阶国家电视网的机会
I mean, I still have a-a shot at a national desk.
但是曼迪却不想结束这段感情
And Mandy didn't want it to end.
她可能威胁你要去向哈维报告
She could've threatened to tell Harvey.
什么  不  不  你们在开玩笑吧
What? No, no. Are you kidding?
不是的  曼迪和我一样
No, Mandy didn't want this to get out
也不想让这事传出去
Any more than I did.
你们不会往外说的  对吧
You're not gonna tell, are you?
昨晚10:28你在哪里
Where were you last night at 10:28?
在丽嘉酒店参加
Uh, at a press party at the Ritz-Carlton
维嘉手机的新闻发布会
for the launch of the Vega smartphone.
曼迪有没有跟你说
Did Mandy say anything to you
前几天她去了一趟急诊室
about going to the E.R. a couple days ago?
没有  她没说  不过话说回来
No, she didn't mention it, but then again,
她上个周实在表现得很奇怪
She was acting pretty strange last week.
怎么个奇怪法
What do you mean?
她不肯告诉我  但是我觉得
Well, she wouldn't tell me, but I had the feeling
她不仅仅是因为我们的事而郁闷
it was more than just us she was upset about.
一定还有别的事烦着她
There's something else that was bothering her.
看起来化妆室那些女人说的
Well, it looks like those makeup ladies
关于曼迪有绯闻的事是真的
were right about Mandy's affair,
只是猜错了绯闻的对象
They just had the wrong guy.
卡塞尔  关于他说的其他事你怎么想
Castle, what about the other stuff that they said
他说地下情迟早是要被揭穿的
about how secret romances are impossible to keep hidden?
你也听到了迈尔斯是怎么说的了
I mean, you heard Miles.
我不想被谎言憋到透不过气
I don't want to drown in a sea of lies.
别担心  嘴对嘴人工呼吸我在行
Well, if it's any comfort to you, I do know mouth-to-mouth.
埃斯波
Hey, Espo.
发现蹊跷之处
Found something weird.
给曼迪治疗的急诊医生那条线
The E.R. Doc that treated Mandy?
原来是治疗严重哮喘发作的
It turns out it was for a severe asthma attack.
这不奇怪  我们知道曼迪有哮喘
That's not weird. We know that Mandy had asthma.
因此她才没法上电视台的直升机
That's why she couldn't go up in the station helicopter.
接下来就是蹊跷的地方了
Which brings me to the w-weird part.
她是乘WHNY电视台的新闻直升机抵达急诊室
She arrived at the E.R. in the WHNY news chopper.
着陆后
She landed on the helipad,
飞行员扶她进去的
and the pilot walked her inside.
好  谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
她患有哮喘
With her asthma,
还坐直升机干嘛
what was she doing up there
怎么会没人知道
and why did no one know about it?
有一个人知情
There is one person that knew about it,
那个直升机飞行员
the helicopter pilot.
你去哪  帅哥
Where you going, pretty boy?
现在八点半
It's 8:30.
马上就到你和克里斯蒂娜的部分了
It's time for your segment with Kristina.
你该去化妆了
Gotta get you into makeup.
没关系  我去处理
It's okay. I'll take care of it.
好吧  我不在的时候别结案
Okay. D-don't solve the case without me.
我不该那样做
Look, I wasn't supposed to, okay?
但几天前
But a few days ago,
她带着装有1000美元的信封来找我
she showed up with an envelope stuffed with 1,000 bucks,
说她只需调用直升机20分钟
said she needed the chopper only for 20 minutes,
还得保密
and nobody could know.
她说过为什么要用直升机吗
Did she tell you why she needed it?
没有  不过一定相当重要
No, but it must have been important.
我喜欢曼迪
Look, I liked Mandy--
活泼  长得又好看
Bubbly, easy on the eyes.
我想帮她
I wanted to help her out.
但我们起飞后  她拿出了那些设备
But then we get up there, she's got all this equipment,
说想飞到泽西上空
and she wants to fly over Jersey.
为什么要去新泽西
Why New Jersey?
问倒我了
Beats me.
我只知道那样会耗掉更多的机油
All I know is, it's more fuel,
我上司也许会发现
and my boss might notice.
那你飞了吗
Okay, so did you do it?
是的  我们在泽西上方盘旋了几分钟
Yeah. We were over Jersey for a few minutes,
之后她呼吸困难
but then she started breathing heavy.
她没带吸入器
She didn't have her inhaler,
于是我径直飞去了医院
so I flew straight to the hospital.
你知道她有什么企图吗
D-do you have any idea what she was up to?
不知道
No.
我跟她说我不想离开纽约的时候
When I told her I didn't want to leave New York,
她说"事关生死"
she said, "It's a matter of life or death."
她或许是对的
I guess maybe she was right.
我再也不会
That was-- that was the last time
带手提电脑去咖啡馆了
I took my laptop into a coffee shop.
那么
So...
作为一位英俊潇洒的畅销小说作家
As a handsome, best-selling author,
我敢肯定总是有女人
I'm sure you must have women
对你投怀送抱
throwing themselves at you all the time.
每个人都要背负各自的重任嘛
Well, we all have our crosses to bear.
是啊  你个苦行僧
Yes, you are such a martyr.
就是说你现在没有意中人咯
So no one special in your life right now?
我呢
I, uh...
没有  目前没有
No. Uh, actually, no. No one special.
现在我单身
I'm single right now.
好极了  因为有个问题
That's good, because there's a question
我憋了很久了
I've been wanting to ask you.
明晚你愿意和我共进晚餐吗
Will you have dinner with me tomorrow night?
我真是受宠若惊
Wow. Wow. I'm flattered.
但我不得不拒绝
But I have to decline.
快点  卡塞尔
Come on, Castle.
我们还有三秒就进广告了
There's only three seconds until commercial.
我
I, uh, uh...
就是啊  你等什么呢  说啊
Exactly. What are you waiting for? Hello.
我们马上要你的答复
We're gonna need an answer.
不
No.
老实说  我很乐意
Uh, actually, I would love to.
-是约会哦  -太好了
- It's a date. - Great.
《冰冻希特》现已上架
"Frozen Heat"-- it's on bookshelves now.
广告之后我们继续对话理查德·卡塞尔
We'll have more with Richard Castle after the break.
这是最完美的掩饰
I'm telling you, it's the perfect cover.
如果他们知道我和克里斯蒂娜约会
No one's gonna suspect us
没人会怀疑我们
If they know I'm going out with Kristina.
卡塞尔  跟科塔拉打得火热  好样的
Yo, Castle, nice work with Coterra, bro.
瞧见没  完美
See? Perfect.
是啊  很完美
Yeah, it's perfect.
你和她的约会打算进行到哪个环节
So how far do you plan on taking this date with her?
我打算带她去高级餐馆
I'm taking her out to a fancy dinner,
就是那种所有人都能看到我们的浪漫餐厅
someplace romantic where everyone will see us,
说不定会登在"第六页"上
Maybe even end up on "Page Six."
那该有多棒啊
How great would that be?
是啊  "棒"极了
Yeah, that'd be so-- that'd be really great.
你没意见吧
You are okay with this, right?
没有  怎么了
Yeah. Yeah. Why?
问问而已
Just askin'.
曼迪的直升机之旅查到线索了吗
So what did we learn about Mandy's helicopter ride?
我们找到了她在公寓用的设备
Well, we found the equipment that she used in her apartment.
就是她从瑞贝卡·弗格那里偷来的设备
It turns out, it's all the stuff she stole from Rebecca Fog.
瑞贝卡·弗格
Rebecca Fog.
你是说那不是恶作剧
But you mean, it wasn't a prank?
她确实用了这些东西
I mean, she actually used this stuff?
-是的  -为什么
- Ahem. -Why?
我们希望你能帮我们解惑
Well, we were hoping you could tell us.
如果当时她是在直升机上
Uh, well, if she was up in the chopper,
她应该用了这台毒素监测器
She must have been using the direct tox monitor.
毒素监测器  当然了
The direct tox monitor, of course.
你根本就不知道那是什么
You have no idea what that is.
完全摸不着头脑
No, not a clue. Mm-hmm.
它是种检测空气质量的设备
Uh, it's an instrument to test air quality.
可她是个享有盛名的美女主播
But she was a glorified spokesmodel.
她到底在干什么
What the hell was she up to?
有办法查清楚吗
Is there any way to find out?
可以  监视器存储了测量数据
Yeah, the, uh, monitor stores measured data.
等等
Whoa. Wait.
-这不可能  -怎么了
- Well, this can't be right. - What?
数据显示有高浓度的苯乙烯
It's indicating high levels of styrene.
那不寻常吗
And is that unusual?
是的  苯乙烯是种危险的化学品
Yeah, styrene's a dangerous chemical.
长期接触会导致严重的呼吸系统的问题
Prolonged exposure could lead to severe respiratory problems.
比如哮喘
Like asthma.
曼迪一做完那个测试哮喘就发作了
Mandy had an asthma attack right after she did that test.
记得雷吉所说吗
And remember Reggie's statement?
他说曼迪在医院的时候
He said Mandy was hanging out
总和那些生病孩子在一起
at the hospital with those sick kids.
说不定两者有关联
Maybe there's a connection.
她人很好
She was really nice.
她说她也得了很严重的哮喘
She said she had asthma, too,
她还说哮喘无法阻止我前行
and that it didn't have to hold me back.
每次医生来的时候  他们只和我妈交谈
When the doctors come in, they only talk to my mom.
只有那个天气预报员阿姨想和我聊天
The weather lady, she actually wanted to talk to me.
她都问过你一些什么事
And what kinds of things did she ask you about?
很多  学校还有朋友之类的
Lots of things, like school and friends.
上一次  她问我在哪里打棒球
Last time, she asked me where I played baseball.
你怎么回答
And what'd you tell her?
在康维运动场
Conway Field.
她有没有说为什么问这个问题
Did she tell you why she wanted to know?
她觉得那可能与我得哮喘有关
She thought it had something to do with my asthma.
失陪
Excuse me.
我与曼迪拜访过的每个孩子的母亲
Hey, so I just talked with the mothers of all the other patients
都逐一谈过
that Mandy visited with at the hospital,
她们都说了同一件事
and they all said the same thing--
曼迪问了他们关于在康维运动场练习的事
Mandy asked them about their practices at Conway Field.
我来猜猜  康维运动场位于新泽西
Let me guess. Conway Field's in New Jersey.
具体是在尤宁县
Union County to be exact.
我已经跟医院工作人员们谈过了
So I spoke with admissions at the hospital,
他们说尤宁县重症哮喘患者
and they said that numbers for severe asthma patients
数量在不断增加
are up for that neighborhood.
作为一名患有哮喘的气象播报员
Well, as a weather girl and someone with asthma,
曼迪深知空气质量对
Mandy would've understood the impact of air quality
呼吸道疾病患者的影响
on someone with respiratory illness.
那纸条上写着
The note said,
"如果走漏半点风声  我就杀了你"
"if any of this gets out, I'll kill you."
假如曼迪发现了导致空气中含有苯乙烯
What if Mandy found out what or who was responsible
的罪魁祸首
for the styrene in the air?
他们因此杀了她
It's possible they had her killed.
根据兰尼载曼迪采集
So based on the direction that Lenny traveled
空气样本飞过的地区来看
while Mandy took air samples,
他们经过的八家工厂都在康维运动场附近
they flew over eight factories, all near Conway Field.
八家工厂之中  只有一家会产生苯乙烯
And of the eight factories, only one produces styrene--
卡祖利地毯公司
Cazuli Carpeting.
苯乙烯是他们加工过程中的化学副产品
It's a chemical byproduct of their manufacturing.
再看看他们家货单下方的图标
And check out the bottom of one of their bills.
眼熟吗
Look familiar?
他们的厂标和曼迪收到的
Their logo has the same design
死亡威胁上的一样
that's on the death threat Mandy got.
而且卡祖利地毯的所有者
Yeah, and the owner of Cazuli Carpeting,
乔治·卡祖利是个恐吓的老手
George Cazuli, is no stranger to carrying out threats--
人身攻击  虐待配偶
Assault and battery, spousal abuse,
把一个竞争对手的工厂烧个精光
and the attempted arson of one of his competitor's factories.
那就都说得通了
Well, then it all makes perfect sense.
一个火爆易怒的工厂主
A hotheaded factory owner
被理想主义的女气象播报员指控
is confronted by an idealistic weather girl
说他是导致空气有毒的罪魁祸首
who accuses him of pumping poison into the air.
如果她的指控公之于众
And if her allegations went public,
他就得面对刑事指控
he'd face criminal charges,
工厂也就倒闭了
his factory would be shut down.
只不过卡祖利先"毙"了她
Only Cazuli shuts her down instead.
卡祖利先生  请坐
Mr. Cazuli, have a seat.
我看过够多的《法律与秩序》
I've seen enough episodes
知道你们在盘算些什么
of "Law & Order" to know how this works.
你们想要诱导我说出一些
You think you're gonna trick me
有悖事实的话
into saying something that ain't true?
我告诉你们
I'll tell you what,
在律师来之前  我什么都不说
I ain't saying another word till my lawyer gets here.
没问题
Not a problem.
在您的律师到达之前  卡塞尔先生与我
Mr. Castle and I will just use that time
就利用这段时间研究一下您的档案吧
to go through your file before your lawyer gets here.
那样也许会有帮助
Oh, yeah. That'll be helpful.
档案真厚啊
Wow. That's a thick file, huh?
我们来看看
Okay, let's see.
六个月前  卡祖利公司改良了他们的地毯垫面技术
Six months ago, Cazuli modified their carpet backing
以延长产品的使用寿命
to create a longer-lasting product.
谁不想要超耐用的地毯呀
Who doesn't want longer-lasting carpet?
是的  可不幸的是  垫面的生产过程
Yes, but unfortunately, this process
会释放出一种叫苯乙烯的有害化学物质
released a harmful chemical called styrene.
小量的苯乙烯释放是正常的
Now that's normal in small doses,
但卡祖利工厂的释放量
but in the case of Cazuli's factory,
已经远远超过合法上限
they were way over the legal limit.
糟糕了
Well, that's terrible.
卡祖利先生知道这事吗
Did Mr. Cazuli know?
他怎么可能不知道
You know, it's hard to imagine that he didn't, right?
不管怎样  根据调查
Anyway, according to this,
当地气象播报员曼迪·麦克斯
local weather girl Mandy Michaels
把苯乙烯超量释放和哮喘患者数量上升
made a connection between elevated levels of styrene
联系起来
and an increase in asthma cases.
这对卡祖利公司来说可是个坏消息
This is not sounding good for Cazuli.
我在想  他知不知道她在调查这事
You know, I wonder if he was aware she was looking into this.
事实上
As a matter of fact,
卡祖利地毯公司的一个接待员
a receptionist at Cazuli Carpeting
接受警方询问称
went on record saying that
几天前曼迪曾来过工厂
Mandy showed up at the factory a few days ago.
我打赌她是去跟卡祖利对质这件事
And I bet you she went there to confront Cazuli.
卡祖利一定知道
Cazuli had to know that
要解决问题就得停止生产
the cost of shutting down production
而那样会给工厂带来巨大的损失
to address the problem would've been sky-high.
怪不得曼迪会收到恐吓信
You know, that explains the threatening note that Mandy got.
"如果走漏半点风声  我就杀了你"
"If any of this gets out, I will kill you"?
这图案和卡祖利地毯公司的标志一模一样
Hey, this matches exactly the Cazuli Carpeting stationery.
那就是她出现在公园的原因
That's why she was at the park.
环境保护署
The Environmental Protection Agency's
就在转角处
right around the corner.
我想你的假设是对的
You know what? You might be right about that.
之前我给环保署打电话时
When I called them, they confirmed
他们说曼迪本来要把一些东西
that Mandy was on her way there
送到他们那里的去检测
to drop something in the after-hours box.
我认为卡祖利为了自保而杀人灭口
I think Cazuli killed her to keep her from turning him in.
够了
All right, enough!
这个播报员在插手一些
This broad was sticking her nose into something
和她半点关系也没有的事
that was none of her business.
她带着她的那些破证据来见我
She shows up, she's all high, she's all mighty
一副道貌岸然的样子  我告诉她
with her stupid-ass file of evidence, and I told her,
告诉她"滚出去  别来瞎搅合"
I told her to "scram, get outta here, beat it!"
"如果再让我见到你在这一带晃悠
"And if I ever see your face around here,
我就要你好看"
you're gonna regret it."
我跟她说过这些
I told her.
她说  如果我不把工厂关闭
She says to me, if I don't close everything down,
她就要把我们曝光
she's gonna expose us.
那个破纸条
The friggin' note--
那个纸条只是想把她吓走
The note was to scare her away a little bit.
起效了不是吗
Seemed to work, right?
因为之后我再没听到她的消息
'Cause I never heard from her again.
够了  别缠着我
Come on. Give me a break.
我以为这破事都已经了结了
I thought this mess was over with.
谢谢您  卡祖利先生
Thank you, Mr. Cazuli.
干什么谢我
Oh, yeah. For what?
谢您承认了杀死曼迪的动机
For admitting to motive
及曾恐吓过她
and to threatening Mandy.
什么
What?
他就交给你了  律师先生
He's all yours, counselor.
你死哪儿去了
Where you been?
卡祖利的律师在为他超量释放苯乙烯商讨认罪减刑
Cazuli's lawyer is looking for a plea on the styrene violation.
那谋杀罪呢
What about the murder rap?
宣称他是清白的
Claims he's innocent.
不幸的是  我们无法确定案发当晚
Yeah, but unfortunately, we got nothing
卡祖利在案发现场
that places Cazuli there the night of the murder.
如果我们没有确凿的证据
Look, if we can't physically tie him to it,
这一切都是推断
then all we have is speculation.
没有证据  他就会被释放
Without evidence, he's gonna walk.
这里有些东西你们得看看
There's something you're gonna want to take a look at.
卡祖利办公室的搜查令申请下来了
Search warrant came through on Cazuli's office.
我们发现了曼迪留给他的文件
We found the file that Mandy left with him.
在她的研究中
Now in her research
这张地毯厂烟囱的照片
is this picture of their smokestack.
看起来是在地面上拍的
It looks like it was taken at street level.
没错  现在再看看拍摄时间
Exactly. Now take a look at the timestamp.
这张照片摄于上周四
This picture was taken last Tuesday
下午5:47
5:47 p.m.
根据照片上太阳的位置
Based on the position of the sun,
技术部门说时间是正确的
tech confirmed that the time was correct.
有什么意义吗
Meaning what?
这说明除非曼迪有分身术
Meaning unless Mandy could be at two places at once,
否则她不可能拍下这张照片
she couldn't have taken that photo.
5:47她正在直播气象
She was on air at 5:47.
那么照片是谁拍的
So who took the picture.
她有搭档
She had a partner.
所以曼迪才会对卡祖利说 "他们"会曝光他
Which is why Mandy told Cazuli "they'd" expose him.
如果她还有拍档
Well, if she had a partner,
那他们为什么还不现身呢
then why haven't they come forward?
也许他们被卡祖利吓到了
Maybe they're afraid of Cazuli.
如果我们能找到他们
If we can find them,
他们或许有确凿的证据给卡祖利定罪
they might have some info on Cazuli that'll nail him.
不如我们点份晚餐再研究一下
You know what? Why don't we order dinner and work through?
等下  卡塞尔
Wait a minute. Castle.
今晚你不是要和克里斯蒂娜·科塔拉约会吗
Don't you have a date with Kristina Coterra tonight?
是啊
Yes, I do.
糟了  我迟到了
And--oh, crap! I'm late.
快去吧  别因为我们耽搁了
Yeah, well, don't let us keep you.
我去赴约真的没问题吗
Uh, are you sure you're okay-- are you okay with this?
开玩笑吧  那可是克里斯蒂娜·科塔拉
Okay? Are you kidding? It's Kristina Coterra.
再说  你什么时候让警务工作
Yeah, besides, since when have you let cop work
妨碍你忙碌的社交生活了
get in the way of your busy social life?
是啊  去吧  约会愉快
Yeah, I mean, go. Enjoy your date.
是啊
Right.
好吧
Okay.
回头打给你
I'll call you later.
询问案子的进度
To check on the case.
伙计们  我们
Okay, guys, let's just get...
还是专心工作吧
back... to work.
惊喜
Surprise.
你在...你怎么...我
What are you--how--I--
我以为我们约好在餐厅见
I thought we were meeting at the restaurant?
我知道  但是这样更浪漫
I know, but this is so much more romantic--
你和我
You, me...
还有牡蛎
Some oysters.
你带了牡蛎来
Oh, wow. You got oysters in there?
帮我们助兴
To get us in the mood.
还有一些沾了巧克力的草莓
Also some chocolate-covered strawberries.
我
I...
我和电视台的人都谈过了
Well, I spoke with everyone at the station,
包括她男朋友
including her boyfriend.
没人承认是同伙
No one admits to being the partner
也没人知道她在干什么
or even knowing what she was working on.
电话记录里也没什么线索
There's nothing in her phone records either.
我们肯定漏掉了什么
Yeah, well, there's gotta be something that we're missing.
说到缺了什么
Speaking of missing something,
今晚的约会卡塞尔应该超级兴奋才对啊
Castle should be way more excited about his date tonight.
为什么
Why?
《明星审查》上说
According to "Celebrity Examiner,"
克里斯蒂娜以她超多的比基尼收藏
Kristina is notorious for seducing famous men
勾引男明星而"声名"远扬
with her extensive bikini collection.
怎么了  是珍妮买的  放在咖啡桌上
What? Jenny buys it, and it just happened
恰好翻开在了那一页
to be open to that page on the coffee table.
你想说什么呢
What's your point?
还不明显吗
Isn't it obvious?
她今天肯定要对他用上这招
She's totally gonna put the moves on him.
不可能  不会的
No way. Not gonna happen.
感谢你表现得成熟了一点点
Thank you for actually showing some maturity.
肯定是卡塞尔先下手为强
He's totally gonna put the moves on her.
难道你们不觉得他现在干不出那种事了吗
Don't you guys think that he's actually evolved beyond that by now?
他是个男人  他还活着  所以
He's a man, he has a pulse, so...
不觉得
No.
你知道吗
You know,
自从我在红地毯上看到你
ever since I saw you on that red carpet--
你的面容
Mm, that face of yours--
我一直等着这一刻
I have been waiting to do this.
既然你都等了
Well, if you've been waiting
那么久了  不如再多等几分钟
that long, why not wait a few minutes more?
你要去哪
Where you going?
去冰箱把草莓放进去
To the fridge to put away these strawberries.
可不想让巧克力都化掉
Wouldn't want the chocolate to melt.
至于巧克力我能想到更好的用途哦
I can think of a better use for that chocolate.
好了
Okay.
克里斯蒂娜  我们谈一下
Kristina, let's talk about this for a second.
你想要谈谈吗
Oh, you want to talk?
我只是...  我们
Well, I just-- what are we--
我们这是在干吗
What are we-- what are we doing here?
卡塞尔  约会如何
Hey, Castle. How's your date?
你要...
What are you--
后退后退
Get back. Get back.
卡塞尔
Castle?
别担心
Don't worry.
我来搞定
I got it.
我来帮忙  我来帮忙
Okay, I'll help. I'll help.
你拨通了理查德·卡塞尔的电话  你真幸运
Hi, you've reached Richard Castle. Lucky you.
既然已经清理干净了
Now that that's out of the way,
我们刚刚进行到哪了
where were we?
牡蛎
Oysters.
跳过牡蛎吧
Ooh, let's skip the oysters.
确定吗  因为我恰好
Really? 'cause I happen to be--
你干嘛要欲擒故纵呢
Why are you playing so hard to get?
我真的没有  我只是
I'm really not. I just--
你有
You are.
从来没有男人拒绝过我
You know, no man has ever said no to me.
曾经有一个
Well... there was one.
真的吗  似乎是个有趣的故事
Really? That sounds like an interesting story.
说说吧  他怎么得逞的
Tell me about him. How did he get away?
我向你保证
I assure you...
绝对不是我的问题
It had nothing to do with me.
卡塞尔
Castle?
我...
I, uh...
我知道谁是凶手了
Uh, I know who the killer is.
我尝试了一切办法来摆脱她
Look, I tried everything to get away.
我躲在了吧台下面
I-I hid under the counter.
躲进了浴室
I was hiding in the bathroom.
我还试图
At one point, I tried to pull
在钢琴下演出《恐怖角》的情节
a "Cape Fear" up under the piano.
但是我进去的时候
Yet when I walked in,
她在沙发上跨坐在你身上
she was straddling you on the couch.
她就像欲望终结者
Right? She's like the terminator of sexpots.
那是什么意思
What is that even supposed to mean,
她一个劲儿地套近乎吗
she just keeps on coming?
不  我  那是
No, I--that's...
我会答应这个约会的唯一理由
The only reason I went on the date in the first place
是因为你觉得在众人面前保持单身很重要
was because you made a big deal about being single in public.
卡塞尔  我有12通未接电话
Castle, I have 12 missed phone calls
都是那个体育播报员打来的
from chip the sportscaster
都是因为他以为我单身
because he thinks that I'm single,
但那并不意味着
but that doesn't mean
我要让他穿着泳裤骑在我身上
that I'm gonna let him mount me in his speedos
来证明我单身
just to prove it.
你没告诉我他给你打电话了
You didn't tell me he called.
不是吧  你还想打吃醋牌
Really? You're gonna play the jealousy card now?
听着  我会补偿你的  好吗
Okay, look, I'll make it up to you, all right?
你想要什么都行
Whatever you want.
我想要的是
What I want is not to have
不想脑海中出现你的脸
this image of a bikini-clad woman
夹在比基尼女的双峰之间
stuffing her boobs in your face.
想办法实现吧
So good luck with that.
人家查出凶手都不给甜头吗
Don't I even get credit for figuring out who the killer is?
不给
No.
本周随后几天  将有增温趋势
Later in the week, we'll be seeing a warming trend.
哈克斯顿先生
Mr. Haxton.
能借一步说话吗
Can we have a word?
我要直播头条新闻了
Uh, I'm about to go live with a story.
我们也是
So are we.
我和克里斯蒂娜·科塔拉进行了一场有趣的对话
I just had a very interesting conversation with Kristina Coterra.
她告诉我  你是唯一一个
She told me that you are the one man
拒绝了她的男人
who's rejected her advances in the past.
对  唯一的男人
Yep, the one man.
我不知道这有何关系
Well, I don't see how that's relevant.
她的自尊心受了创伤
Well, her pride was hurt
于是她调查了一番
So she did a little digging.
发现你的确有一段地下恋情
Turns out, you did have a secret relationship,
只不过不是跟曼迪
Just not with Mandy.
她发现你有一个不为人知的男友
She discovered you have a boyfriend that no one here knows about.
我的私生活跟你们没关系
Well, my... personal life's none of your business.
通常情况下  是的  但是
Normally, yes, but it became our business
当我们发现你对我们说谎时  就有关系了
when we found out that you lied to us
关于你为什么去曼迪的公寓
about why you were at Mandy's apartment
以及你们争吵的原因你都说谎了
and about what you were fighting over.
-是你拍了这张照片吗  -不是
- Now did you take this photo? - No.
那就有趣了
Wow, that's funny.
因为在你的公寓我们发现了一部相机
Because a search of your apartment turned up a camera
既有这张还有很多其他的照片
with this and other photos on it.
她是你的搭档
She was your partner.
她在帮你搜集资料
She was helping you with a story,
你为什么不报案
So why didn't you come forward?
只有一个我能想到的原因
Well, there's only one conceivable reason--
因为是你杀了她
Because you killed her.
她是我的同事和朋友
She was a colleague and a friend.
我为什么要杀她
Why would I kill her?
因为她发现了惊天内幕
Because she uncovered the expose of a lifetime.
这么爆炸性的事件  必须经过法律部门的核实
A story that big, it has to be vetted by legal,
那要花上几周  甚至几个月的时间
that can take weeks, even months.
但是曼迪等不了那么久
But Mandy couldn't wait that long,
因为孩子们不断患病
not while kids were getting sick.
所以她决定把证据交给美国环保署
So she decided to turn the findings over to the E.P.A.
那样的话
At which point,
你就没了独家报道
you lose your big exclusive.
你什么时候有过独家报道啊
Now when was the last time you had a big exclusive?
这太疯狂了
This is crazy.
太扯了
No, this is crazy.
你们认为我为了报道杀了人吗
You--you think I killed someone for a story.
我们知道凶手是你
We know it was you, Miles.
我们发现了多处枪击残留物
We found gunshot residue on the clothes in your hamper,
在滑雪面具上
on the ski mask,
衬衫上
the shirt.
你们得明白
You have to understand...
那是意外
It was an accident.
我只是想吓吓她
I only meant to scare her.
我想如果我能把材料拿回来
I thought if I could just get those files back,
就能阻止她
I could stop her.
我就可以像她保证那样爆独家新闻了
I'd be able to break the story like she promised.
但是她跟我拉扯起来
But she fought me.
她奋力反抗  她过来夺枪
She fought me, and she went and grabbed for the gun.
她干嘛要反抗
Why would she fight me?
我是说我都不知道枪上膛了
I mean, I-I didn't even know the gun was loaded.
电视台经理确认了
Well, the station manager confirmed,
迈尔斯职位本就岌岌可危
Miles was on thin ice.
想要挽救职业生涯的唯一办法
The only way he could save his career
就是一则爆炸性新闻
was to break a splashy story,
所以他跟曼迪达成协议帮助她
So he made a deal with Mandy to help her
换取独家报道的机会
in exchange for the exclusive.
之后她背叛了他
Right, and then when she betrayed him,
他从新闻发布会派对溜出去与她对质
He snuck out of the press party to confront her,
之后事情就急转直下
and then things just got bad from there.
我得说
I've gotta say,
曼迪调查时很勇敢
pretty brave of Mandy to take up that cause.
完全不像是人们说的那样
Not what you'd expect from what people said about her.
她的同事都以为很了解她  真是好笑
It's funny how her coworkers thought they knew her so well,
她隐瞒他们过着神秘的生活
and she had this whole secret life she was hiding from 'em.
是啊
Yeah.
很晚了  我闪人了
It's late. I'm gonna get outta here.
我也走
Yeah, me, too.
陪你走
Walk you out?
不用了
Uh, no, thanks. I'm good.
晚安  伙计们
Good night, guys.
-晚安  -晚安
- Good night. - Night.
晚安
Well, good night.
-晚安  -晚安  卡塞尔
- Good night. - Night, castle.
看
Look.
是雷吉
It's Reggie.
最后  我们来看看
And finally, here is number one
这周体育十大事件的头条
on this week's top ten sports moments of the week--
该视频是由雷吉·布雷克粉丝寄来的
This one sent in from a Reggie Blake fan.
想要硬闯见布雷克
This is what happens when you try
这就是下场
to barge through to see the Blake.
我想那些狂热的粉丝
Yeah, I'm guessing those eager fans
没有拿到签名
did not get an autograph.
你替我挨了那一拳
Yo. You took that punch for me.
你不必那样做的
You didn't have to do that.
那是搭档该做的  不是吗
Well, it's what partners do, right?
走  喝酒去
Come on. Let's go get a beer.
我买单
I'm buying.
好
Cool.
除了体育酒吧哪儿都行
Uh, anywhere but a sports bar.
肯定不去体育酒吧
Definitely not a sports bar.
我错了
I'm sorry.
我错了  我不该赴约
I'm sorry. I should not have gone on that date.
我该拒绝她的
I-I... I should've said no.
那你为什么不拒绝
Then why didn't you?
我不在行啊  我是说假装单身
Well, I'm no good at this. Pretending to be single--
好吧  卡塞尔  我也不在行
Yeah, but, castle, neither am I.
我最不想担心的事就是
And the last thing I want to do
你跟其他女人在一起
is have to worry about you with other women.
我事先声明  我没打算跟她上床
Well, uh, for the record, I-I wasn't gonna sleep with her.
我知道
I know.
那不是我要说的
Look, that's not even the point.
我要说的是
The point is, is...
我无所是从
I don't even know how to do this.
你还记得迈尔斯说过
Do you remember when Miles said that
地下恋情终会崩塌
It's inevitable that this will fall apart,
注定会承受不住压力
That it's destined to implode?
我要提醒你
Uh, just a reminder,
迈尔斯是个说谎的凶手
Miles is a lying killer.
但是
But...
也许他们会发现
Okay, maybe people find out,
也许我们无法在一起工作
and maybe we won't get to work together,
也许我们会承受不了
and maybe we'll implode.
但我们也有可能一直美好下去啊
Or maybe we'll continue to be amazing.
重点是  我们没有答案
The point is, we don't have the answers.
我们得带着问题去生活
We just have to live with the questions and...
找到答案
Find our way.
好吧
Okay, can...
那我们这样吧
Well, can we just start here then?
我们嘴上说在跟别人约会
Can we say that we will talk about dating other people,
但其实没有跟别人约会
but we won't actually date other people?
我能做到
Yeah. I--no, I can do that.
很好  反正我有枪
Okay, good, because I have a gun,
你别无选择
and you don't really have a choice.
-这很明显  -是的
- Clearly, I don't have a choice. - No.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
亲不了
I can't.
才刚刚发生
It's--it's too soon.
我总是看到夹在她双峰间的你的脸
I just--I keep seeing her boobs in your face.